Hey. Answer the damn
question, you twit.
What do you want to do?
I want to join the Scouts...
...and slaughter every Titan I can!
Ah. Not bad.
Erwin. I'll take
responsibility for him.
Let the higher-ups know.
I don't necessarily
trust him, though.
If he betrays us
or goes out of control,
I'll kill him on the spot.
The top brass won't complain.
Because I'm the only
one cut out for this.
You're in.
I'll make you a
member of the Scouts.
I won't let your deaths be meaningless
even if I'm the last one standing
In both hands, Gloria
What sings is Sieg
On my back, Flügel der Freiheit
Clenched determination to my left chest
What slashes across is Linie der Torheit
Soaring across the azure skies
Flügel der Freiheit
"Can't Look into His Eyes Yet"
"Eve of the Counterattack, Part 1"
Hey, is it true that a
Titan sided with humans?
That's obviously just a rumor.
I bet the recapture plan failed
and loads of people from
Wall Rose are gonna flee here.
"Interior of Wall Sina"
If that happens, we'll have
food shortages in no time flat.
Man, please tell me
those Wall Rose people
aren't gonna show up here
with this Titan friend of theirs...
"Wall Sina"
"Wall Rose"
This is huge news!
"Interior of Wall Rose"
We have a Titan on our side now!
Who knows, maybe we
can even retake Wall Maria!
It's almost like it's... it's...
...our savior!
Oh!
Savior, huh?
Throughout history, commoners
have always been a rash lot.
I can see this triggering a
revolt against the central powers...
Not if we, the Military Police,
dispose of Eren Jaeger first.
I won't let those Scout
Regiment deviants have him.
Fall in!
Hail to the Premier!
It's certainly hot.
Commander Pyxis.
You're the top commander
of the Garrison Regiment
and I'm a commanding officer
of the Scout Regiment.
Won't some disapprove of
us meeting like this?
Oh, you're as straight-laced
as the rumors say.
Still, this is just a morning walk.
We only met by happenstance.
So, let's chat during our little stroll.
Have you heard that the Military Police
wants to take custody of Eren Jaeger?
Yes, I received word yesterday.
They're going to hold
a deliberation on the matter.
Mm.
It falls entirely
to Zachary to decide
whether the Scouts get him
or the Military Police gets him.
Zachary...
You mean Premier Dhalis Zachary?
He oversees the three regiments:
the Military Police, the Garrison
Regiment, and the Scouts.
He will base his decision on one thing:
whether his existence is
beneficial or harmful for humanity.
If he deems him a detriment, he won't
hesitate to have Eren executed.
Right there, on the spot, even.
I don't want them to kill Eren.
But, unfortunately,
many in the Garrison Regiment
are fearful of Eren's ability.
The most I can do is avoid
agreeing with the Military Police.
Are the odds in your favor?
No.
But we do have a proposal ready.
Whether or not it'll work depends
on how the debate unfolds.
You'll be playing it entirely
by ear, in other words?
Our line of work
takes us outside the walls.
We always play things by ear.
It seems you're
not so uptight after all.
This has been a nice walk,
Commander Smith.
A debate over Eren?
What for?
I'm not really sure,
but I think it's about
what they plan to do with him.
What do you mean?
My guess...
...is they're going to decide
if he should live or die...
Are Mikasa Ackermann
and Armin Arlelt here?!
Yes!
You are ordered to attend this
afternoon's deliberation as witnesses!
Excuse me! I need to use the toilet...
You just went!
Please give me some water!
Hey!
Know your place, monster.
Monster...
Yeah, that might be the case...
But am I so terrifying that
I need to be restrained this much?
I guess I can't blame them, though.
Even I don't understand any of this.
At least they haven't killed me yet...
Come to think of it,
they weren't afraid of me at all.
What are they doing now?
What happened to all the others?
Just hang on a little longer.
We'll try to arrange things somehow.
How many days has it been since then?
What's going on on the outside?
I'm... not going to spend the
rest of my life in here, am I?
So you're Eren, huh?
You okay? How are things?
I'm sorry you've had to wait so long.
But now you have a
chance to finally get out.
Except...
...you'll have to put these on.
I'm Hange Zoë, a section
commander in the Scout Regiment.
And this is Miche Zacharius,
also a section commander.
U-Umm...
Oh, he always sniffs people like
that when he first meets them.
He has a habit of
laughing through his nose.
I doubt he means anything by it.
Oddness aside, he is skilled enough
to be a section commander.
Oops!
Sorry! I just prattled on, didn't I?
We're already here, but...
No, it'll be okay!
It's actually better if I don't explain!
W-Wait...!
It's selfish of us, but all we
can do is put blind faith in you.
--Good luck!
--Huh?!
A courthouse?
I was in the basement of a courthouse?
Get moving!
Kneel down!
What's with all these people?
In fact, what is this trial even about?!
Guys!
Shall we begin?
You are Eren Jaeger,
a soldier who has sworn
to give his life for the people.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Given the extraordinary circumstances,
this deliberation will be held
as a court-martial;
regular law will not apply,
in other words.
I have full decision-making
authority in this matter,
which includes determining
whether you should live or die.
Just as I thought!
Any objections?
No, Sir.
Your astuteness is appreciated.
I'll get right to the point.
As expected, concealing your
existence has proved impossible.
Unless we publicly disclose your
existence in one fashion or another
we risk the outbreak
of a new, non-Titan threat.
It falls to me to decide which
regiment should take charge of you.
The Military Police Regiment...
Or the Scout Regiment...
Now let's hear what the
Military Police Regiment proposes.
Yes, Sir.
I, Nile Dawk, Commander
of the Military Police,
offer the following proposal.
We believe that, after a thorough
examination of Eren's body,
he should be disposed of immediately.
It's true that his Titan ability
helped thwart this latest incursion.
However, his existence is now
stirring up rebellious ideas as well.
As such, after he's provided us
with as much information as possible,
he will be made a
fallen warrior of humanity.
There's no need!
He is vermin that
has defiled and infiltrated
--...the walls built by God's great wisdom!
--He's with the Wall cult!
--He should be killed at once!
--Everyone ignored them five years ago...
--Pastor Nick. Please remain quiet.
--...but they've really grown in power.
Next, let us hear the Scout Regiment's idea.
Yes, Sir.
I, Erwin Smith, 13th Commander
of the Scout Regiment,
offer the following proposal.
We intend to accept Eren as an
official member of the Scout Regiment
and utilize his Titan
ability to retake Wall Maria.
That is all.
Hmm? That's all?
Yes, Sir.
With his help, we can reclaim Wall Maria.
I believe it is clear what
our utmost priority should be.
I see.
Tell me, from where
would you launch this operation?
Pyxis.
The wall has been completely
sealed in Trost District, correct?
Yes.
I doubt its gate will ever open again.
We hope to depart from
Calaneth District, to the east.
From there we would
approach Shiganshina
by establishing a
new route from scratch.
Just a damn minute!
Shouldn't we be
sealing all the gates now?!
The gates are the only part
the Colossal Titan can break!
If we can just reinforce them,
we'll never get attacked again!
Shut up, you merchant dog!
With a Titan's help
we can return to Wall Maria!
We can't put up with any more of
your childish heroics!
You have a big mouth on you, swine.
What guarantee is there
that the Titans will kindly
wait while we bolster the gates?
When you say "we",
you mean the friends you're protecting
so you can fatten yourselves up.
Are you pigs blind to the people
who struggle to survive
off what little land is left?
I'm just saying that all we have to
do is seal the gates if we want to live!
Hold your tongue, you miscreant!
You would suggest
that humans meddle with
Wall Rose, a gift from God?!
That wall is a divine miracle that
transcends human understanding!
--Do you still not realize...
--It's their fault...
--...that humanity must not touch it!
--...it took so long to arm the tops of the walls.
They have that much support and power now.
They're a bad sort.
Th-That's disrespectful!
Shut it, you lousy priest!
What?!
Order!
I ask that you save your personal
sentiments for another venue.
I wish to make certain
of something, Mr. Jaeger.
As a soldier, can you
continue to serve humanity
by controlling your Titan ability?
Yes, Sir! I can!
Oh?
But it says here in this
report about the Trost battle
that just after transforming, you swung
your fists at Mikasa Ackermann.
He doesn't remember
that he wasn't in control...
What, you expect me to lie in a report?
Hiding this fact wouldn't do
humanity any good.
And who is Mikasa Ackermann?
I am, Sir.
You, huh?
Is it true that Jaeger,
in Titan form, attacked you?
It's in Eren's best interest
that you answer honestly.
Yes. It's true.
I knew it! A Titan's a Titan!
I tried to kill Mikasa?!
Me?!
However...
He also saved my life on two
prior occasions while in Titan form.
The first time,
just as I was about to
fall into the hands of a Titan,
he intervened and protected me.
The second time, he protected
Armin and me from a bombardment.
I ask that you take these facts
into consideration as well.
Just a minute!
I believe that her testimony
is also very driven by personal feelings.
It should be noted that Mikasa Ackermann
lost her parents at a young age
and was taken in by the Jaeger family.
What's more, our own
investigation into this matter
led us to a most surprising discovery.
Eren Jaeger and Mikasa Ackermann,
at the age of nine,
stabbed and killed
three adult robber-kidnappers.
Even if it was in self-defense,
we cannot help but
question his basic humanity.
Should we really place
personnel and funds in his hands,
not to mention the very fate of humanity?!
Yeah!
He's clearly a Titan that's snuck
in by taking the form of a child!
Her too!
I bet she's not human at all!
Yeah! We should
dissect her just to be safe!
Hold on!
I might be a monster,
but she has nothing to do with this!
Nothing at all!
--Like we can believe you!
--It's the truth!
--She is one if you hafta protect her!
--No!
No... It's not like that.
But you're all using speculation
to push your own selfish agendas!
Wh-What?!
In fact...
Is this bad?
...none of you have even seen
a Titan, so why are you so afraid?!
Maybe I should stop talking...
No, I'm gonna tell 'em
everything I think!
What's the use of having power
if you're not going to fight?!
If you're afraid of fighting for
your lives, then help me!
You... cowards!
What?
Just shut up...
...and invest everything in me!
Take aim!
Yes, Sir!
Huh?
Wait, Mikasa!
My personal belief
is that pain is the best tool
for teaching discipline.
What you need now
is to be taught a lesson,
not given a talking-to.
And you happen to be
in perfect kicking position.
Wait, Levi!
What?
That's dangerous.
What if he gets mad
and turns into a Titan?
Don't be silly.
You guys are gonna
dissect him, aren't you?
When he was transformed,
he apparently managed to kill twenty
Titans before running out of strength.
As an enemy, his intelligence
makes him all the more dangerous.
Even so, I could handle him just fine.
But could you?
Whoever dares to torment
him had better think long and hard.
Can you actually kill him?
Sir. I have a proposition.
What is it?
Eren's Titan ability includes
too many uncertainties
which pose an ever-present danger.
As such, we will place Eren
under Captain Levi's supervision
and conduct a recon
mission outside the wall.
With Eren accompanying you?
Yes, Sir.
Based on the results of said mission,
you can decide if Eren
has control over his Titan ability
and if his existence
is of benefit to humankind.
Supervising Eren Jaeger, huh...
Can you do this, Levi?
Oh, I can most definitely kill him.
The real problem is
that there's no middle ground.
I've reached my decision.
Man, talk about harsh...
--I bet it hurts.
--A little...
--So, how exactly does it hurt?
--Huh?
I'm sorry about that.
But it did get you placed in our custody.
Yes...
The pain was worth it.
It let us play our trump card
when it would be most effective.
You have my admiration.
Eren. I look forward to working with you.
R-Right! Thank you, Sir!
Tell me, Eren.
Y-Yes?
Do you resent me?
N-No.
I understand it was
a necessary performance.
Good, then.
Still, you didn't have to go so far.
You knocked his tooth out!
--See?
--Don't pick that up. It's disgusting.
This is a precious sample of its own.
Eren. Be thankful you aren't
getting dissected by people like her.
Don't compare me with them.
I would never kill Eren.
Hey, Eren. Let me
see inside your mouth.
The tooth...
...has already grown back...
If, by chance, I'm not me
then who's to say that you're you?
Can you pick up the pieces of your heart
that fell apart like a broken sand castle?
The voice of someone calling out
changed into ringing in my ears
It's as if time has stopped
Now wake up
I made my way out of the deep darkness
I fled like a swift wind
We used to be like living corpses,
but now we head beyond the walls
Let's meet again
in a place not on any map
After achieving his dream
of joining the Scout Regiment,
Eren discovers that the Scouts
are a band of people
who seek change, as well as a haven
of eccentrics and oddballs.
"Special Operations Squad"
"Eve of the Counterattack, Part 2"